Howard Teichmann Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Writings File, 1857-1996 (Box 42-137)
  - Film
    - Zoom! (formerly titled We're Losing the Sun )
      - Outlines, undated
      - Drafts, undated, (2 folders)
      - Final version, undated
  - Miscellany, undated, (2 folders)
  - Plays (Box 96)
    - Accustomed as I Am, 1954
    - Blind Girl with a Sword See Containers 115-116, The Woman in the Case
    - A Casual Miracle See Containers 104-106, Miss Lonelyhearts
    - College play, 1961, undated
    - Double Exposure, undated
    - Exile, undated, (2 folders)
    - For the Rich They Sing See also Containers 102-103, In the Money
      - Correspondence, 1988
      - Drafts
        - 1984
        - Undated, (2 folders); (4 folders) (Box 97)
        - Miscellaneous pages, undated
      - Typescript, 1984
    - George S. Kaufman, 1981, undated, (2 folders)
    - The Girls in 509 (Box 98)
      - Box office statements, 1958-1959, (2 folders)
      - Contracts, 1958-1960
      - Correspondence, 1957-1981, undated, (5 folders)
      - Financial records, 1958-1967, undated
      - Programs, 1959-1960
      - Publicity and reviews, 1958-1960, undated See also Oversize
      - Royalty statements, 1958-1979, 1986-1988, undated
      - Set design model (Donald Oenslager), undated See Oversize
      - Scripts, 1958-1962, undated, (4 folders) (Box 99)
    - Good Will Ambassador, 1960-1962
    - Howe and Hummel
      - Background information, undated
      - Contracts, 1948-1956, 1977
      - Correspondence, 1948-1968, 1977, undated, (3 folders) (Box 100)
      - Miscellany, undated
      - Notes, 1951, undated, (2 folders)
      - Outline, 1952
      - Scripts
        - 1952, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 101)
        - Undated, (6 folders); (1 folder) (Box 102)
    - I Found April, 1953, (2 folders)
    - In the Money See also Containers 96-97, For the Rich They Sing
      - Correspondence, 1975
      - Notes, undated
      - Outlines, undated
      - Scripts, undated, (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box 103)
    - Jewish one-act play, undated
    - Julia, Jake, and Uncle Joe
      - Box office statements, 1961
      - Contracts, 1959-1960, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1959-1961, undated
      - Scripts, undated, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 104)
      - Set designs, 1961
    - The Little Shares See Containers 111-114, The Solid Gold Cadillac
    - Mimsy, undated
    - Miscellany, 1945-1948, 1960-1967, 1973-1982, 1991, undated
    - Miss Lonelyhearts
      - Box office statements, 1957, 1973
      - Contracts and copyright, 1955-1958, 1965, 1972, undated, (2 folders)
  - Plays (Box 105)
    - Miss Lonelyhearts
      - Correspondence, 1955-1965, 1972-1985, undated, (6 folders)
      - Miscellany, 1942, 1956-1957, undated
      - Programs and publicity, 1957, undated See also Oversize
      - Reviews, 1933, 1982, undated
      - Royalty statements, 1956-1973, 1981
      - Scripts
        - 1957, (3 folders)
        - Undated, (1 folder); (5 folders) (Box 106)
      - Set designs (Jo Mielziner), 1957
    - Mrs. ’Arris Goes to Paris, 1959-1962, undated See also Oversize
    - Outboard Motor, undated
    - Postscript, 1944-1945, (3 folders) (Box 107)
    - A Rainy Day in Newark
      - Contracts, 1963-1964
      - Correspondence, 1962-1965
      - Miscellany, 1963-1967, undated See also Oversize
      - Scripts
        - Outline and miscellaneous pages, undated
        - First draft, undated, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 108)
        - Typescripts, undated, (6 folders); (1 folder) (Box 109)
    - The Relief at Li Ko, undated, (3 folders)
    - Rich Man, Poor Man, 1957-1958
    - Satire on charities, 1960, (2 folders)
    - The Seventh Circle, 1945
    - Single Girls and Home Cooking, 1962, (2 folders)
    - Smart Aleck (Box 110)
      - Box office statements, 1981
      - Contracts, 1977-1981, 1991, undated, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1975-1982, undated
      - Miscellany, 1934, 1977-1981, undated
      - Programs and publicity, 1979-1981, undated See also Oversize
      - Reviews, 1979-1981
      - Scripts
        - 1984
        - Undated, (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box 111)
    - The Solid Gold Cadillac
      - Contracts, 1953-1965, 1974-1996, (5 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1953-1988, undated, (9 folders) (Box 112)
      - Financial records, 1965 (Box 113)
      - Miscellany, 1956, undated
      - Programs, 1953-1959
      - Publicity, 1953-1957, 1965, undated See also Oversize
      - Reviews, 1953-1957, 1965, 1976
      - Royalty statements, 1954-1990, undated, (2 folders)
      - Scripts
        - Drafts
          - 1953, 1976
          - Undated, (3 folders) (Box 114)
        - The Little Shares, undated
        - Miscellaneous pages, undated
        - Scene outlines, 1953, undated
        - Typescripts, undated, (3 folders)
        - Working production script, undated
    - United Nations play, 1952-1953, undated, (7 folders) (Box 115)
    - Untitled (main character, “Zisi”), undated
    - The Woman in the Case
      - Contracts, 1947-1948
      - Correspondence, 1947-1948, undated
      - Publicity, 1947, undated
      - Scripts (Box 116)
        - Drafts, 1947, undated, (7 folders)
        - Typescripts
          - 1947, (2 folders)
          - Undated, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 117)
      - Synopsis, undated
  - Radio
    - All American Snack Sack, 1941
    - American Red Cross, 1945
    - Angela Is Back, 1945
    - Better Be Right, 1940-1945, undated
    - By the Dawn's Early Light, 1940, undated
    - Campbell Playhouse, 1940-1944, 1986
    - Cavalcade of America
      - “Abraham Lincoln in Washington,” 1940
      - “The House Near Little Dock Street,” 1949
      - “Many a Watchful Night,” 1945-1952, undated
      - Miscellany, 1941, 1950
    - City Desk, “Crystal,” 1941-1948, undated
    - Come and Get It, 1940, undated, (1 folder) (Box 118)
    - Command Performance, undated
    - Contests, 1940, undated
    - The Destroyers, undated
    - Enough and on Time, 1942-1943, undated, (2 folders)
    - Father Brown, undated (Box 119)
    - The Fighting Senator, 1945-1948, undated
    - For Valor See Container 124, Homegrown Heroes
    - Ford Theatre
      - Contracts and correspondence, 1947-1951, undated
      - Miscellany, 1947-1948, undated
      - Scripts, 1947-1948
        - Vol. 1
        - Vols. 2-4, (3 vols.) (Box 120)
        - Vols. 5-7, (3 vols.) (Box 121)
        - Vols. 8-10, (3 vols.) (Box 122)
        - Vols. 11-13, (3 vols.) (Box 123)
    - Gertrude Lawrence's Revlon Revue, 1943 (Box 124)
    - Homegrown Heroes, 1940-1942, undated
    - The Incredible Christopher Lamb, 1941
    - Job for Tomorrow, 1945
    - Letters from the Front, 1943
    - Listen to America! undated
    - Mercury Theatre on the Air
      - Correspondence, interview, and notes, 1939-1952, 1979, undated
      - “The Count of Monte Cristo,” undated
    - Miscellany
      - Correspondence, 1940-1952, 1982, undated
      - Newspaper clipping, undated
      - Notes, 1942, 1950, undated
      - Scripts
        - 1941-1948
          - Vol. 1
          - Vols. 2-4, (3 vols.) (Box 125)
        - Undated, (2 folders) (Box 126)
      - Story outlines and proposals, 1940-1945, undated
    - The Nature of the Enemy, 1942
    - The Nervous Wreck, 1941
    - The New Theatre, 1951-1956
    - Newsreel for Thanksgiving, 1946-1947
    - One Girl's Struggles, undated
    - Road of Life
      - Contracts and correspondence, 1944-1948, undated
      - Outlines, 1945-1947, undated, (4 folders) (Box 127)
      - Scripts, 1945-1947, undated
    - Short, Short Story Program, “Turning Point,” 1940
    - Stories America Loves
      - Correspondence, 1940-1943
      - “Dodsworth,” 1941-1942
      - Miscellany, 1941 (Box 128)
      - “So Big,” 1942, (3 folders)
      - “The Virginian,” 1941, (3 folders) (Box 129)
    - Story of the Year, 1948
    - Theatre of Valor, 1950
    - Theatre U.S.A. See also Container 31, American National Theatre and Academy
      - Budget, 1949, undated
      - Contracts, 1948
      - Correspondence
        - 1948
        - 1949-1951, undated, (2 folders) (Box 130)
      - Miscellany, 1948-1949, undated
      - Publicity, 1948-1949, undated
      - Reviews, 1948, undated
      - Scripts, 1948-1953, undated
      - World Telegram libel action, 1948-1952, undated
    - They Live Forever, 1942, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 131, Box 132)
    - This Is Howard Teichmann, News and Information Service
      - Drafts, 1976, (2 folders)
      - Typescripts, 1975-1976, undated, (5 folders)
    - Tomorrow and Tomorrow, undated
    - U.S.A. Canteen, “Jane Froman,” 1952-1953
    - Valiant Lady
      - Contracts and correspondence
        - 1942, (2 folders)
        - 1943-1946, undated, (2 folders) (Box 133)
      - Notes, undated
      - Outline, 1940-1945, (6 folders)
      - Publicity, 1949, undated
      - Scripts, 1942-1944, undated (Box 134)
    - World's Fair, New York, N.Y., 1940
    - Young Doctor Malone, 1945
  - Short stories
    - “High Dive,” undated
    - “His Lordship Rides Back,” circa 1938
    - “How I Became Stengel's Successor as Manager of the New York Yankees,” 1960
    - “Jack-O-Lanterns, Their Purposes and Uses,” undated
    - “Marvin, the Marvelous Monster,” undated
    - “Mimsy,” undated
    - Miscellany, undated
    - “Night and The River,” 1938
    - Untitled, undated
  - Speeches, 1957-1974, 1980-1981, undated See also Oversize, (5 folders)
  - Television (Box 135)
    - Columbia Broadcasting System
      - Financial records, 1957, undated
      - Ford Motor Company's 50th Anniversary Show
        - Contracts, 1953
        - Correspondence, 1953-1963, 1978, undated
        - Newspaper clippings, 1953
        - Notes, 1953, undated
        - Outlines, 1953
        - Scripts, 1953, (5 folders); (2 folders) (Box 136)
      - Great Authors
        - Correspondence, 1957
        - Scripts, circa 1957
      - Miscellany, 1952
      - Slezak and Son
        - Correspondence, 1945-1961, undated
        - Notes, undated
        - Scripts, 1956
      - U.S.A. Canteen
        - Contracts, 1952-1956
        - Correspondence, 1952-1953
    - Gillette Christmas Program, 1954
    - “Let George Do It, the George S. Kaufman Comedy Cavalcade,” 1972
    - “Make a Hit with America,” 1950
    - “The Man Who Was Comedy,” undated
    - Media Productions
      - Contract, 1949
      - Correspondence and memoranda, 1948-1950, undated
      - Minutes, 1948-1949
      - Miscellany, 1949, undated
    - Miscellany, 1950-1953, 1976, undated (Box 137)
    - National Broadcasting Company, NBC News
      - Correspondence, 1975-1976
      - Salary statements, 1975-1976
    - National Educational Television and Radio Center, Trio, a Program of Essays
      - Correspondence, 1962
      - Miscellany, 1962
    - Production development, 1948-1964, 1972-1981, undated, (2 folders)
    - Showtime U.S.A. See also Container 31, American National Theatre and Academy
      - Contracts, 1950, undated
      - Correspondence, 1949-1951
      - Financial statements, 1951, undated
      - Miscellany, 1950-1951, undated
      - Report, 1951
    - “Tomorrow and Tomorrow,” undated
    - Wonderful World of Entertainment
      - Correspondence, 1960
      - Scripts, 1959, undated, (2 folders)
- Miscellany, 1941-1987 (Box 138-141)
  General notes and photographs. Correspondence, financial records, and printed matter regarding Milton Shubert's work for the United States Navy Department during World War II.
  - Notes (Box 138)
    - 1944-1952, 1972, 1981, 1987, (2 folders)
    - Undated, (7 folders) (Box 139)
  - Photographs, 1933-1945, 1959, undated, (2 folders) (Box 140)
  - Shubert, Milton
    - Correspondence
      - 1941-1942, (6 folders)
      - 1943, 1970, undated (Box 141)
    - Financial records, 1941-1942, undated, (3 folders)
    - Miscellany, 1941-1942, undated, (3 folders)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1942, undated
    - Photographs, undated
    - Printed matter, 1941-1942, undated
- Oversize, 1905-1982 (Box OV 1-OV 13)
  Account book, photographs, posters, sheet music, and a three-dimensional stage design.
  Arranged and described according to the series, containers, and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Personal File (Box OV 1)
    - Teichmann Productions
      - Account book, 1946-1960 (Container 30)
  - Organizations File (Box OV 2)
    - University of Wisconsin, Madison, Wis.
      - Haresfoot Club
        - Poster, 1905 (Container 41)
  - Writings File (Box OV 3)
    - Books
      - Published
        - Fonda: My Life as Told to Howard Teichmann
          - Photograph, undated (Container 66)
          - Publicity (Box OV 4)
            - Poster, 1982 (Container 68)
        - Smart Aleck: The Wit, World, and Life of Alexander Woollcott (Box OV 5)
          - Photographs, undated (Container 93)
    - Plays (Box OV 6)
      - The Girls in 509
        - Publicity and reviews
          - Poster, undated (Container 98)
        - Set design model (Donald Oenslager), undated (Container 98) (Box OV 7)
      - Miss Lonelyhearts (Box OV 8)
        - Programs and publicity
          - Poster, undated (Container 105)
      - Mrs. ’Arris Goes to Paris (Box OV 9)
        - Sheet music, undated (Container 106)
      - A Rainy Day in Newark (Box OV 10)
        - Miscellany
          - Poster, 1964 (Container 107)
      - Smart Aleck (Box OV 11)
        - Programs and publicity
          - Poster, undated (Container 110)
      - The Solid Gold Cadillac (Box OV 12)
        - Publicity
          - Posters, undated (Container 113)
    - Speeches (Box OV 13)
      - Poster, undated (Container 134)